

Mohammad Tanzeel Ur Rehman

Email: mohammadtanzeel.ur@gmail.com Phone: (+92) 3260750391

Phone: (+36) 307354381

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-tanzeel-ur-rehman-3b3414216/

Github: https://github.com/tanzeelkhan95

Date of birth: 17/06/2000 Nationality: Pakistani

ABOUT ME -

Computer Science Graduate having vast experience in multiple programming languages and other sets of digital skills. Enjoys creative problem solving and getting exposure on multiple projects. Loves to work as a team and getting my tasks done as smooth as possible.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/09/2018 - 01/04/2019]

Intern and Teacher Assistant

Westminster Academy

City: Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- 1. Managed Attendances of teachers and students through Microsoft excel and worked as a receptionist
- 2. Teacher Assistant for GCE A-levels Math's and Computer Science students

For reference the following link shows the certificate of completion: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1nwjyn6liAAxHFR3bczaeGrT4ZRr1 xPI/view?usp=sharing

[15/07/2022 - 15/09/2022] **Web Developer Intern**

Lime Light Renhold

City: Oslo

Country: Norway

Completed tasks such as creating 3D CSS Flip cards using SCSS preprocessor, customizing to advertise a product. Creating a responsive web design | webpage portfolio with JavaScript and Bootstrap and Designing a webpage featuring CSS parallax scrolling effect.

For reference the following link shows the certificate of completion: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1|LS8zdvaKjypAh95nwD3xhvcG9ziF2Te/view?usp=sharing

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[01/09/2014 - 30/08/2018]

GCE O Levels and A Levels

Westminster Academy www.westminster.edu.pk

Address: Islamabad, Pakistan

[01/09/2019 - 27/01/2023]

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

University of Debrecen www.edu.unideb.hu

Address: Debrecen, Hungary

DIGITAL SKILLS -

Programming Languages

Java | C | C# | C++ | Python

Web Development

PHP | NodeJS, Express, MongoDB | Handlebarsjs | CSS3 | Javascript | Embedded JavaScript (EJS) | Bootstrap | JSON | HTML5

Others

MATLAB | 3D Printing & Modeling (tinkerCAD) | Game Development (Unity) | Basics of R | Cloud Computing | Mobile App Development (Android Studio) | MySQL | Machine Learning / Reinforcement Learning | Selenium

PROJECTS

Coin Game (Java FX) for Software Engineering Project

https://github.com/tanzeelkhan95/javafx_project

This Game was made with Java FX. Originally made in GitHub Classroom as a project for Software Engineering and Technologies subject. The game is played on a 4*4 cell board. Initially the four coins are placed in the middle. The goal of the game is to move each coin to a corner cell. In a move, one of the coins must be moved either horizontally or vertically by 1, 2, or 3 cells. A coin can be moved if and only if all of the following conditions hold:

- 1. It is adjacent to one or more coins either horizontally or vertically and The target cell is empty and all cells between the coin and the target cell are empty.
- 2. When a new game is started the program must ask for the name of the player.

Web App Development (Thesis Project)

https://github.com/tanzeelkhan95/Thesis-Project

My thesis work focused on a full-stack development project where I built an e-commerce web app using Visual Studio Code IDE. For the frontend, I designed and developed the web app to be responsive across different devices using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript. On the backend, I created a server utilizing JSON and REST APIs, and for data storage, I employed a database system like MongoDB to store customer login information, addresses, and order history. To ensure enhanced security, I implemented AES encryption for encrypting customer login passwords, ensuring that passwords remain inaccessible to managers while handling customer data.

Automation Testing Using Selenium

https://github.com/tanzeelkhan95/SoftwareTestingProject

Swag Labs Website Automation Testing project. For this project, I employed the Selenium Framework and tools like Cucumber to test the features of a demo website called saucedemo.com, covering login scenarios, incorrect combinations, categories, and checkout functionalities.

Amongus Runner (Project 1) for Software Methodologies

https://github.com/unidebSDMGroup/AmogusRunner

A group project of a small game made for Software Methodologies subject using Unity and C# class involving a player chasing and AI player and having to dodge obstacles. The objective of the game is to gain the highest score.

Media Player (Project 2) for Software Methodologies

https://github.com/unidebSDMGroup/MediaPlayer

A Group project for Software Methodologies subject made by using Java FX, the project is a video editor allowing a user to import videos, images and audio files and place them on the screen in the positions they want aswell as mute and unmute audio.

CERIFICATIONS -

[21/05/2020] Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks

[20/05/2023] Career Essentials in Software Development by Microsoft and Linkedin

[21/05/2020] LambdaTest Test Automation Professional Certificate

HONOURS AND AWARDS -

[21/05/2020] **Letter of Merit Awarding institution:** Cisco, University of Debrecen

A letter of merit signed by Cisco CEO Chuck Robbins that is awarded for scoring 75% or above on the course final exam, acknowledging the excellence achieved.

VOLUNTEERING –

[01/07/2017 - 01/08/2017] **WWF International Eco-Internship Programme** Islamabad, Pakistan

LANGUAGE SKILLS -

Mother tongue(s): Pashto

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

Urdu

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2